Your Majesty
Ваше Величество
This is news from Qing Province
Это новости из Цинчжоу
Xie Xuan is implementing reforms there
Господин Се Сюань там проводит реформы
It has sparked a popular uprising
вызвал народное восстание
The gentry
Знать
Nearly turned the provincial capital upside down
чуть не разгромила губернскую управу
This infuriates me
Да злость берёт
Back when Yiyang was besieged
Когда Иян был осаждён
Our volunteer army risked life and death for Your Majesty
мы повстанцы жизнь свою за императора отдали
Only a few old brothers survived
из нас только горстка осталась
I don't believe
Не верю
Your Majesty would abandon us
что император нас теперь бросит
Right
Точно
Let's go
Пошли
Come with me to the capital to see His Majesty
Пойдём прямо в столицу лично к Величеству
To the capital to see His Majesty
В столицу к Величеству
Unfilial son
Предатель
You
Ты
Kneel down
Встань на колени
The sages' books are for reading
Книги мудрецов предназначены для чтения
Not for you to actually use
а не для того чтобы применять их на практике
His Majesty sent you to reform in the Chen family's stronghold
Император отправил тебя проводить реформы в родном гнезде семьи Чэнь
Can't you see the pattern?
и ты совсем не понимаешь намёка
To achieve great things
Чтобы добиться великого
There must be sacrifices
нужно чемто жертвовать
It's unavoidable
неизбежны
This is what
Это ты сам
Father taught me
учил меня раньше отец
Your Majesty
Ваше Величество
Chancellor Xie requests an audience
советник Се просит о встрече
Summon him
Впусти
Your Majesty
Ваше Величество
The reforms cannot continue
реформу нельзя больше продолжать
In Qing Province, nobles are intertwined with nobles
В Цинчжоу знать связана со знатью
Personal connections are layered
связи связаны со связями
If we continue reforming
Если продолжать реформу
It's no longer something Xie Xuan
это уже не то
Can handle
что Се Сюань сможет выдержать
Your servant begs Your Majesty to revoke the order
Прошу Ваше Величество отменить приказ
Don't let Xie Xuan wade into this muddy water anymore
Не заставляйте больше Се Сюаня лезть в эту мутную воду
Your servant has already lost a daughter
Я уже потерял одну дочь
Now only this one son remains
остался только этот сын
Your Majesty
Ваше Величество
Your Majesty, this old servant begs you, Your Majesty
Ваше Величество старый слуга умоляет Вас Ваше Величество